Survival of the fittest.
La survie du plus apte.
It's the law of the jungle.
C'est la loi de la jungle.
There's always someone trying to take what's yours.
On tente sans arrךt de nous voler notre place.
How do I know?
Comment je le sais ?
It almost happened to me.
ַa a failli m'arriver.
Hi-yah!
Hi-ha !
Tim Templeton...
Tim Templeton,
quit monkeying around.
arrךte de faire des singeries.
Hot dogs are getting cold.
Les hot-dogs refroidissent.
Hot dogs?
Des hot-dogs ?
At least, this is how I remember it.
En tout cas, c'est le souvenir que j'en garde.
All right, buddy, let's eat.
Allons manger, mon grand.
You see, I was seven years old...
Voyez-vous, j'avais sept ans.
and back then, you relied on your imagination.
ְ cet גge-lא, on vit dans son monde imaginaire.
When I wasn't exploring the Congo...
Quand je n'explorais pas le Congo,
I was a deep sea diver.
j'יtais scaphandrier professionnel.
Tim!
Tim !
Our hero!
Notre hיros !
Don't worry, Mom and Dad.
Ne vous inquiיtez pas.
I got this!
Je m'en occupe !
Grab on!
Accrochez-vous !
Some days, I rescued my parents.
J'ai souvent sauvי mes parents.
That way!
Par lא !
Other days, they rescued me.
Et ils m'ont sauvי aussi.
- I'm losing control. - Tim, look out!
- Je ne le maמtrise plus. - Tim, attention !
Tree!
Un arbre !
You're breaking up!
Perte de signal !
Slow down, Tim!
Ralentis, Tim !
- Turn, Tim. - Turn!
- Tourne, Tim. - Tourne !
- Are you hurt? - I'm okay.
- Tu t'es fait mal ? - ַa va.
Show Mommy your teeth.
Montre tes dents א maman.
It was just the three of us.
On יtait trois.
The Templetons.
La famille Templeton.
And three is the perfect number.
Trois, c'est le chiffre idיal.
Interesting fact...
Fait remarquable :
did you know that the triangle is the strongest shape found in nature?
le triangle est la forme naturelle la plus solide.
I was the luckiest kid ever.
J'יtais l'enfant le plus chanceux du monde.
My parents even had cool jobs.
Mes parents avaient des emplois super.
They worked for the biggest pet company in the world...
Chez le plus grand יleveur d'animaux de compagnie, Chiot et Cie.
- Yes, Mr. Francis? - Puppy Co needs you.
- Oui, M. Francis ? - Chiot et Cie vous veut.
It's go time.
C'est parti.
They worked in a department called "Marketing..."
Ils travaillaient א la mise en marchי
where they got to launch new products.
de nouveaux produits.
Even though my parents worked really hard...
Mךme si mes parents travaillaient fort,
they still made just enough time for me.
ils ne me nיgligeaient pas.
Three stories, five hugs, and my special song, right?
Trois contes, cinq cגlins et ma berceuse favorite ?
You got it!
Mais bien sr !
Blackbird singing in the dead of night
Un merle chante sous les יtoiles
Take these broken wings and learn to fly
Malgrי tes ailes cassיes Tu dois apprendre א voler
All your life
Toute ta vie
You were only waiting For this moment to arise
Tu as attendu la chance De t'יlancer dans le firmament
Hey, Tim. How would you like to have a baby brother?
Tim, aimerais-tu avoir un petit frטre ?
No, thanks. I'm enough.
Non merci. Je me suffis.
Life was good. Life was perfect.
La vie יtait belle. Rien א redire.
But as I drifted off to sleep...
Mais en m'endormant,
something my parents said got me thinking.
je songeais aux paroles de mes parents.
Where do babies come from?
D'oש viennent les bיbיs ?
The day I got a little brother started like any other day...
Le jour de l'arrivיe de mon petit frטre יtait pareil א tous les autres,
but little did I know...
mais j'ignorais alors
my life would never be the same.
que ma vie ne serait plus jamais la mךme.
Wake up, little halflings! It's 7:00 a.m.
Debout, petits enfants-nains ! Il est 7 h.
Wake up, little halflings!
Debout, petits enfants-nains !
Morning, Wizzie!
Bonjour, le mage !
What great adventure lies in wait for you today?
Quelle grande aventure t'attend-elle aujourd'hui ?
Oh, yeah!
Ouais !
My parents always said that I had an overactive imagination.
Mes parents ont toujours dit que j'avais une imagination fertile.
But I clearly remember...
Mais je me rappelle distinctement
the baby was delivered in a taxi.
que le bיbי a יtי livrי en taxi.
What the...
Mais que...
Hey!
Hי !
Tim, look who's here.
Tim, regarde qui est lא.
Meet your new baby brother.
C'est ton petit frטre.
Baby what?
Petit quoi ?
Brother.
Petit frטre.
I had a million questions.
J'avais un million de questions.
Who is this guy? Why is he here?
Qui est-il ? Que fait-il ici ?
What's with that outfit?
Pourquoi cette tenue ?
Why's he so fat? Why's he staring at me?
Il est gros. Pourquoi me fixe-t-il ?
Does he know karate? What's going on?
Sait-il faire du karatי ? Expliquez-moi.
That way?
Par lא ?
- Okay.
- D'accord.
Right from the start, he was yelling at people...
Dטs le dיbut, il nous criait dessus,
ordering everyone around.
il nous donnait des ordres.
Oh, you want this?
C'est חa que tu veux ?
One thing was clear. He was the boss.
Une chose יtait claire. C'יtait lui, le patron.
He set up his office, right smack dab in the middle of the house.
Il a installי son bureau au beau milieu de la maison.
He conducted meetings.
Il dirigeait des rיunions.
- You called? - Do you need Señor Squeaky?
- Tu as appelי ? - Tu veux Coin-Coin ?
Lots and lots of meetings.
Des tas de rיunions.
Even in the middle of the night.
Mךme en pleine nuit.
I'm up! I'm up!
Je suis rיveillי !
- We're coming! - We'll be right there!
- On arrive ! - Tout de suite !
If things weren't done to his immediate satisfaction...
S'il n'obtenait pas satisfaction immיdiatement,
he had a fit.
il faisait une crise.
- Where's the bottle? - He has to have his bottle!
- Oש est le biberon ? - Il lui faut son biberon !
He had everyone wrapped around his chubby little finger.
On passait, au petit joufflu, tous ses caprices.
Everyone except for me.
ְ l'exception de celui qui parle.
- Diaper! - Bottle!
- Une couche ! - Le biberon !
Dad! I can't sleep.
Papa ! Je ne peux pas dormir.
I know, bud. Me neither.
Je sais, mon grand. Moi non plus.
The baby needs a lot of attention right now.
Le bיbי a besoin de beaucoup d'attention.
Okay, good talk!
Belle discussion !
- But... - It's okay.
- Mais... - ַa va.
Daddy's here. Daddy's here.
Papa est ici. Papa est ici.
What about me?
Et moi, alors ?
The year: 2057.
En l'an de grגce 2057,
Ensign T-Rex and I are investigating a hostile alien invasion.
matricule T-Rex et moi enquךtons sur une invasion extraterrestre.
It's so much worse than we thought.
C'est plus grave qu'on le croyait.
Mom, he's naked!
Maman, il est nu !
I'm naked!
Je suis nu !
Say "naked."
Dis "nu".
No!
Non !
Who's Mommy's little cutie? Are you Mommy's little cutie?
C'est qui, le petit trיsor א maman ? C'est toi ?
No, he's Daddy's little tough guy, right?
Non, c'est le petit costaud א papa.
You know one of us has to go with Mr. Francis to the pet convention.
L'un de nous doit accompagner M. Francis au congrטs.
In Vegas.
ְ Las Vegas.
- You know what? You should go. - No, no. You should go.
- Tu devrais y aller. - Non, vas-y.
Well, you need a break.
Tu as besoin de repos.
- I'll stay with the baby, and you... - Maybe the baby should decide.
- Je resterai avec le bיbי, et tu... - Qu'il dיcide.
Who do you want to stay with you? Daddy or Mommy?
Qui doit rester avec toi ? Papa ou maman ?
Or Daddy?
Ou papa ?
He wants his mommy.
Il veut que ce soit maman.
Okay, we need to talk!
Je veux vous parler !
In private.
En particulier.
- Sure. - About what, bud?
- Oui. - De quoi, mon grand ?
About the b-a-b-e-e.
C'est au sujet du puceron.
"Y," Tim.
Poupon, Tim.
Why? Because he came out of nowhere!
Il est arrivי de nulle part !
We don't even know him.
On ne le connaמt mךme pas.
How can we trust him?
Comment lui faire confiance ?
Come on, he's just a baby.
Allez, c'est un tout petit bיbי.
Seriously? I'm the only one that thinks there's something weird about this guy?
Sans blague ! Je suis le seul א me mיfier de lui ?
- Oopsie! I got it. - Five-second rule.
- Oups ! - La rטgle des cinq secondes.
Tim?
Tim ?
Look at him! He wears a suit!
Regardez-le ! Il porte un complet !
I know. Isn't it cute? He's like a little man.
Il est mignon, pas vrai ? Un vrai petit homme.
He carries a briefcase.
Il transporte un porte-documents.
Does no else think that's...
Vous ne trouvez pas que c'est...
I don't know, a little freaky?
Disons, un peu louche ?
Well, you carried Lam-Lam around until you were like...
Tu as trimballי Laine-Laine jusqu'א ce que...
This is not about Lam-Lam.
ַa n'a rien א voir avec Laine-Laine.
All babies are different, Tim.
Tous les bיbיs sont diffיrents.
And each one is special.
Et ils sont tous prיcieux.
He's taking over the whole house!
Il veut tout diriger dans la maison !
Are you taking over the house?
Tu veux tout diriger ?
Yes, you are. Yes, you are.
Oui, c'est vrai. C'est vrai.
Trust me, one day you're gonna get to know this little guy...
Crois-moi. Un jour, tu le connaמtras mieux
and you are gonna love him with all of your heart.
et tu l'aimeras de tout ton cur.
Just like we do.
Comme nous.
All of your heart?
De tout votre cur ?
Never.
Jamais.
Hello!
Coucou !
It's time for my three stories, five hugs, and special song!
Trois contes, cinq cגlins et ma berceuse ?
How about one story...
Disons un conte,
three hugs, and my special song?
trois cגlins et ma berceuse ?
Just my special song?
Juste ma berceuse ?
Mom?
Maman ?
Dad?
Papa ?
Hey.
Hי !
What happened to bedtime?
La routine du dodo, c'est fini ?
We'll have it on Monday, Mr. Francis.
Ce sera prךt lundi, M. Francis.
Don't cry! Don't cry.
Ne pleure pas ! Ne pleure pas.
Hello?
Allפ ?
Hello? No, ma'am, not yet.
Allפ ? Non, madame, pas encore.
No, I'm not making excuses.
Non, ce n'est pas un prיtexte.
Yes, ma'am, I know I've been here a long time.
Oui, madame, je sais que חa fait un long sיjour.
Believe me, it feels like my whole life.
J'ai l'impression que חa fait une יternitי.
I'm making great progress with the parents already.
Je fais dיjא de grands progrטs avec mes parents.
The usual procedure, sleep deprivation, hunger strikes.
La procיdure habituelle : manque de sommeil, grטves de la faim.
They're very disoriented.
Ils sont dיsorientיs.
I've got them eating out of the palm of my hand.
Ils me mangent dans la main.
They do everything for me.
Ils m'obיissent au doigt et א l'il.
It's hilarious.
C'est hilarant.
But I think the kid might be on to me.
Mais le petit se doute de quelque chose.
No, I can handle him.
Non, je m'en occupe.
I know how important this mission is to the company.
La mission est cruciale, je le sais.
Mission?
La mission ?
Well, trust me, ma'am. You got the right baby for this job.
Faites-moi confiance. Je suis le bיbי idיal pour ce travail.
Hands up, devil baby!
Haut les mains, bיbי diabolique !
Fart! Poop! Doodie!
Pet, caca et crotte !
I've gotta deal with the k-i-d.
Je dois m'occuper du g-a-r-ח-o-n.
You can talk!
Tu sais parler !
Uh, goo-goo Ga-ga.
Euh, gougou gaga.
No, you can really talk. I heard you!
Non, tu sais parler. Je t'ai entendu !
Fine. I can talk.
D'accord, je sais parler.
Now, let's see if you can listen.
Voyons voir si tu sais יcouter.
Get me a double espresso...
Trouve-moi un double expresso
and see if there's someplace around here with decent sushi.
et de bons sushis dans le coin.
I'd kill for a spicy tuna roll right about now.
Je meurs d'envie de manger un rouleau au thon יpicי.
Get yourself a little something.
Prends-toi quelque chose א manger.
Who are you?
Qui es-tu ?
Let's just say I'm the boss.
Disons seulement que je suis le patron.
The boss? You're a baby! You wear a diaper.
Le patron ? Tu es un bיbי. Tu portes une couche.
You know who else wears diapers?
Tu sais qui porte des couches ?
Astronauts and NASCAR drivers, that's who.
Les astronautes et les pilotes de NASCAR.
It's called efficiency, Templeton.
Question d'efficacitי, Templeton.
The average toddler spends, what? 45 hours a year on the potty?
Un bambin passe en moyenne 45 heures par annיe sur le petit pot.
I'm the boss. I don't have that kind of spare time.
Je suis le patron. Je n'ai pas de temps א perdre.
Well, you're not the boss of me.
Tu n'es pas mon patron.
- I am the boss of you. - No, you're not.
- Je suis ton patron. - Ce n'est pas vrai.
- Am, too. - Are not.
- Ton patron. - Pas vrai.
- Am, too! - Are not!
- Ton patron ! - Pas vrai !
- Am, too.
- Ton patron.
Am, too. Am, too.
Ton patron.
I was here first.
J'יtais ici avant toi.
Just wait until Mom and Dad find out about this.
Attends que maman et papa dיcouvrent la vיritי.
Oh, yeah? You think they'd pick you over me?
Ah oui ? Ils te choisiraient plutפt que moi ?
With your track record?
Avec ta feuille de route ?
You don't know anything about me.
Tu ne sais rien de moi.
So that's how you wanna play it, huh? Let's see.
Tu veux jouer א חa, hein ? Voyons voir.
Templeton, Timothy. Middle name....
Templeton, Timothy. Deuxiטme prיnom...
I'm sorry.
Excuse-moi.
Leslie!
Leslie !
- Mostly C's... - How do you know all that?
- Notes moyennes... - Comment sais-tu חa ?
Can't ride a bike without training wheels?
N'a pas encore abandonnי ses stabilisateurs ?
Even bears can ride a bike without training wheels, Leslie.
Mךme les ours montent א bicyclette sans stabilisateurs, Leslie.
DOB says you're seven.
ֲge : sept ans.
Seven and a half.
Sept ans et demi.
Power nap! You were saying?
Une sieste יnergisante ! Tu disais ?
I'm seven and a half.
J'ai sept ans et demi.
Exactly! You're old.
Tout א fait ! Tu es vieux.
It's time to make way for the next generation.
Il est temps de faire place א la gיnיration suivante.
It's the way of the world.
Ainsi va le monde.
You would never ask your parents for an old toy.
Tu ne demanderais pas un vieux jouet א tes parents.
Lam-Lam?
Laine-Laine ?
Everyone wants the hot, new thing.
Les gens veulent du neuf.
Destroy. Destroy.
Destruction.
- Lam-Lam! - I've got fresh batteries.
- Laine-Laine ! - J'ai des piles neuves.
Boom!
Boum !
Mom and Dad don't even know you.
Maman et papa ne te connaissent pas.
They love me!
Ils m'adorent !
Oh, yeah? Do the math, kid.
Ah oui ? Refais tes calculs.
There's only so much love to go around.
L'amour n'est pas infini.
It's like these beads.
Comme ces boules.
You used to have all your parents' love.
Tu avais tout l'amour de tes parents pour toi.
All their time. All their attention.
Tout leur temps, toute leur attention.
You had all the beads.
Tu avais toutes les boules.
But then I came along.
Puis, je suis arrivי.
Babies take up a lot of time.
Les bיbיs, c'est trטs prenant.
They need a lot of attention. They get all the love.
Ils accaparent l'attention et l'amour de leurs parents.
We could share.
On pourrait partager.
You obviously didn't go to business school.
Tu n'as pas fait d'יtudes commerciales, toi.
Look, Templeton, the numbers just don't add up.
ֹcoute, Templeton, l'יquation ne fonctionne pas.
There's not enough love for the two of us.
Il n'y a pas assez d'amour pour nous deux.
Not enough beads to go around.
Pas suffisamment de boules pour tous.
And then, all of a sudden, there's no place for Tim.
Tout א coup, il n'y a plus de place pour Tim.
Tim doesn't fit anymore.
Tim n'a plus sa place.
Oh, no! What about Tim?
Oh non ! Et Tim, alors ?
So keep quiet. Stay out of my way.
Tiens ta langue. Tiens-toi hors de mon chemin.
Or there's gonna be cutbacks.
Autrement, il y aura des licenciements.
You can't be fired from your own family.
On ne peut pas ךtre virי de sa propre famille.
Can you?
N'est-ce pas ?
Wake up, little halflings! It's 7:00 a.m.
Debout, petits enfants-nains ! Il est 7 h.
Wake up, little half...
Debout, petits...
What's the use?
ְ quoi bon ?
Arise for a nutritious breakfast!
Debout pour un dיjeuner nutritif !
It's 7:00 a.m.
Il est 7 h.
What's wrong, Timothy?
Qu'y a-t-il, Timothy ?
Has that little dwarf made you blue?
Le petit lutin t'a-t-il fait de la peine ?
Mm-hmm.
Hum-hum.
Then I shall cast upon him a great curse!
Je vais lui lancer un terrible sortilטge !
He shall not pass!
Il ne passera pas !
It's no use, Wizzie.
C'est inutile, le mage.
He's got Mom and Dad completely fooled.
Il a dupי maman et papa.
If they knew what I knew, they'd never let him stay.
S'ils savaient ce que je sais, ils le chasseraient.
Perhaps your parents need to be enlightened.
Tes parents devraient ךtre mis au courant.
With a great curse!
Avec un terrible sortilטge !
They shall not pass!
Ils ne passeront pas !
Yeah. I need to enlighten them...
Oui. Je dois les mettre au courant...
with proof!
avec des preuves !
That's what I need, proof!
C'est חa qu'il me faut, des preuves !
Expose his dark magic!
Dיvoile sa magie noire !
Testing, testing.
Test, test.
Maybe they can return him to the store...
Ils pourraient le ramener au magasin
and get their money back!
et se faire rembourser !
We could buy a bouncy house!
On pourrait acheter une maison gonflable !
Godspeed, Tim! It's 8:45 a.m.
Bon vent, Tim ! Il est 8 h 45.
Ninja.
Ninja.
Babies everywhere! They're spreading.
Il y a des bיbיs partout ! Ils se multiplient.
Mom! Dad! What's going on?
Maman ! Papa ! Que se passe-t-il ?
It's an invasion!
C'est une invasion !
It's a play date!
On a invitי des petits amis !
That's a keeper.
Elle est trטs rיussie.
It's a meeting, and you won't be attending.
C'est une rיunion, et tu n'y es pas invitי.
We'll see about that.
Nous verrons bien.
Thank you all for coming here on such short notice.
Merci d'ךtre venus aussi rapidement.
Now, before we begin...
Avant de commencer...
Yes, sir!
Oui, patron !
- Sure is! - Affirmative!
- Absolument ! - Affirmatif !
Jimbo, run some interference.
Jimbo, crיe de l'interfיrence.
Hey!
Hי !
- We babies are having a crisis! - Oh, no!
- Nous, les bיbיs, vivons une crise ! - Non !
- That's awful! - Horrible!
- C'est affreux ! - C'est terrible !
What is it?
Que se passe-t-il ?
It's simpler if I just show you. Teddy, if you please.
C'est plus simple en images. Teddy, s'il te plaמt.
Let's put on a show.
Chauffons les planches.
Here we go!
Allons-y !
Jimbo, hit the lights.
Jimbo, יteins la lumiטre.
You see, babies aren't getting as much love as we used to.
Nous, les bיbיs, ne recevons pas autant d'amour qu'avant.
Why? Have we been bad?
Pourquoi ? On n'a pas יtי sages ?
No, Staci.
Non, Staci.
But I'll tell you who is.
Mais il y a un coupable.
Behold our mortal enemy. Puppies!
Voyez qui sont nos ennemis mortels. Les chiots !
No! That's exactly the problem.
Non ! C'est חa, le problטme.
Puppies? What's the deal with puppies?
Les chiots ? Mais quel est le problטme ?
Throughout history...
Depuis la nuit des temps,
people have loved babies more than anything in the world.
les ךtres humains ont aimי les bיbיs plus que tout au monde.
We've always been a must-have item...
Nous יtions indispensables,
number one on every wish list.
l'article le plus convoitי de tous.
Puppies were merely accessories.
Les chiots n'יtaient que des accessoires.
But all that changed when the puppies began coming out...
Mais tout חa a changי quand les chiots sont arrivיs
with new designer models.
avec ces nouveaux modטles א la mode.
Each one more adorable than the last.
Plus adorables les uns que les autres.
Remember the Labradoodle?
Vous souvenez-vous du labracaniche ?
The Peekapoo?
Du pיkiniche ?
The Chiweenie? Try to say "Chiweenie" without smiling.
Du chihuateckel ? Essayez de dire חa sans sourire.
Not possible. Don't waste your time.
Impossible. N'essayez pas.
We all laughed at the Shar Pei.
Nous nous sommes moquיs du shar-pei.
And now it's number one in China.
Et il fait fureur en Chine.
- Oh, no. - That's terrible!
- Non. - C'est terrible !
- Horrible! - Yes.
- C'est horrible ! - Oui.
And it gets even worse.
Et il y a plus grave encore.
Francis Francis, the CEO of Puppy Co, made this announcement.
Francis Francis, P.D.G. de Chiot et Cie, a fait une annonce.
Teddy, roll the clip.
Teddy, fais jouer la vidיo.
And we are on schedule...
Et le plan va bon train
to release the most adorable puppy ever.
pour prיsenter le chiot le plus adorable de tous les temps.
We're gonna launch it at the pet convention in Las Vegas!
Le dיvoilement officiel aura lieu א la foire commerciale de Las Vegas !
Watch out, world!
La planטte retient son souffle !
It's gonna crush the competition!
Nous יcraserons la concurrence !
- Yay! - No, Jimbo.
- Hourra ! - Non, Jimbo.
No "Yay"! We are the competition!
Pas de "hourra" ! C'est nous, la concurrence !
This is war.
C'est une guerre.
Puppies are winning, and babies are losing.
Les chiots gagnent contre les bיbיs.
Thank you, Teddy.
Merci, Teddy.
And if this new puppy is as cute as we fear...
Si ce nouveau chiot est aussi mignon que חa,
it could put the baby business out of business, baby.
חa pourrait ruiner notre entreprise, les bיbיs.
That's awful!
C'est affreux !
Bad news, baby!
Fatal, bיbי !
What are we going to do?
Qu'allons-nous faire ?
My job is to find out exactly what that new puppy is...
Mon travail est de dיcouvrir ce qu'est ce nouveau chiot
so that Baby Corp can stop it.
pour que Bיbי et Cie sabote tout.
And you're going to help me.
Et vous allez m'aider.
- Genius! - Home run!
- Gיnial ! - Bien vu !
You still got it, boss!
Toujours aussi fort !
Yay!
Hourra !
Yay.
Hourra.
Now, your parents all work for Puppy Co.
Vos parents travaillent א Chiot et Cie.
So have you learned anything from them?
Avez-vous appris quelque chose d'eux ?
- Yes, sir! - Sure did!
- Oui, patron ! - Certainement !
Fantastic. Triplets, go!
Fantastique. Allez-y !
- A. - B.
- A. - B.
- C. - D.
- C. - D.
No, what have you learned about the new puppy?
Qu'avez-vous appris au sujet du nouveau chiot ?
Yay, puppy!
Oui, un chiot !
No, Jimbo! Puppies are evil.
Non, Jimbo ! Les chiots sont l'ennemi.
Staci, read back the notes.
Staci, relis les notes.
I can't read. What's it say?
Je ne sais pas lire. ַa raconte quoi ?
This is my team?
C'est חa, mon יquipe ?
A muscle-head, a bunch of yes men, and a doodler?
Une brute, des moutons et une griffonneuse ?
- Exactly! - Affirmative!
- Oui ! - Affirmatif !
Good call.
Bien vu.
- Oh, yeah! - Nice one, BB!
- Ouais ! - Bien jouי, patron !
Gotcha!
Je te tiens !
Put that cookie down. Cookies are for closers.
Pose ce biscuit. Seuls les vainqueurs y ont droit.
- Let's have another show! - No, Teddy!
- Un autre spectacle ! - Non, Teddy !
- How about a hug? - No more shows!
- Un petit cגlin ? - Fini, les spectacles !
Boss?
Patron ?
- There's plenty of love to go around. - Go to sleep!
- L'amour inonde le monde. - Endors-toi !
Nighty-night.
Bon dodo.
- Boss!
- Patron !
- What? - Parents!
- Quoi ? - Les parents !
It's like they're having their own little meeting.
C'est comme une petite rיunion.
- Isn't that adorable? - Who wants dessert?
- Adorable, non ? - Qui veut du dessert ?
God, this is so humiliating.
Bon sang que c'est humiliant !
Wait until Mom and Dad hear this.
Quand les parents entendront חa !
Hey, Templeton, what you got there?
Hי ! Templeton, qu'as-tu lא ?
Nothing.
Rien.
Hand over the tape.
Donne-moi cette cassette.
Never!
Jamais !
Mom! Dad! Over here!
Maman ! Papa ! Par ici !
- Hi, Timmy! - Hi! Anyway...
- Bonjour, Timmy ! - Bonjour ! En tout cas...
Flower power!
C'est babacool !
You can't get away from Johnny Law, simpleton.
Tu ne peux pas te sauver, espטce d'idiot.
Fasten your seat belt. Let's go!
Attachez votre ceinture. On y va !
Run, run, run.
Cours, cours, cours.
What? Hey!
Quoi ? Hי !
Uh-oh.
Oh, oh !
Run, run, run.
Cours vite.
Catch, catch, catch.
Attrape, attrape.
Yes!
Oui !
Oh, yeah!
Ouais !
Let go, you little...
Lגche חa, espטce de...
Oh, look! The kids are finally getting along.
Regarde ! Les garחons se rapprochent.
That's nice.
Tant mieux.
Sayonara!
Sayonara !
You wanna play?
Vous voulez jouer ?
Let's play.
Jouons, alors.
No!
Non !
Save Boss! Save Boss!
Sauver le patron !
- Get him! - I got him!
- Attrapez-le ! - J'y vais !
You're toast, baby man!
Tu es cuit, homme-bיbי !
Upsies, I need upsies!
En haut. Je dois monter !
Who wants...
Qui veut...
Cheese sticks!
Des bגtonnets au fromage !
Mom, Dad! I've got proof!
Maman, papa ! J'ai des preuves !
Someone can't go down the stairs?
On est coincי en haut des marches ?
Nothing can stop me!
Rien ne peut m'arrךter !
Mom! Dad! Where are you guys?
Maman ! Papa ! Oש ךtes-vous ?
Hello?
Coucou ?
Where did everyone go?
Oש sont-ils tous passיs ?
Mom, Dad! The baby can talk!
Maman, papa ! Le bיbי peut parler !
Oh, can he now?
Tu crois חa, toi ?
Wait, how did you...
Attends, comment as-tu...
Hand over the tape, Timmy.
Donne-moi la cassette.
Or Lam-Lam gets it, see?
Sinon, c'est Laine-Laine qui יcope.
No!
Non !
What's that, Lam-Lam? You want a nose ring?
Rיpטte חa, Laine-Laine. Tu veux un anneau nasal ?
It's really not my scene, but who am I to judge?
Ce n'est pas mon genre, mais je ne juge pas.
And an eyebrow ring? Seems like a little too much, Lam-Lam.
Et un anneau au sourcil ? ַa semble excessif, Laine-Laine.
How's that gonna look in a job interview?
Tu t'imagines, en entretien d'embauche ?
Stop it!
Arrךte !
The tape, Timmy! Or I'm gonna rip, rip, rip.
La cassette, ou alors je le dיchire.
No! Let go!
Non ! Lגche חa !
- You let go!
- Lגche חa !
- Give me the tape! - Give me Lam-Lam!
- La cassette ! - Donne-moi Laine-Laine !
Whoops! Too far.
Oups ! J'ai dיpassי les bornes.
Templeton! Templeton, let's be reasonable.
Templeton ! Soyons raisonnables.
We can be reasonable, right? What are you doing?
Nous en sommes capables, hein ? Que fais-tu ?
You've been asking for this since you got here!
Tu me provoques depuis ton arrivיe !
We can talk about this over a juice box!
Parlons-en en buvant du jus !
Time for juice boxes is over.
Le temps des boמtes א jus, c'est fini.
No, Templeton. You wouldn't.
Non, Templeton. Tu n'oserais pas.
Say bye-bye, baby! You're fired!
Fais tes adieux, bיbי ! Tu es virי !
What are you doing?
Que fais-tu ?
Nothing.
Rien.
My proof!
Ma preuve !
Tim! Explain yourself!
Tim ! Tu as des explications א donner !
Yes, explain yourself.
Oui, vas-y.
It wasn't me! It was the baby's fault.
C'est la faute du bיbי !
The baby's fault?
La faute du bיbי ?
It's true! He can talk.
C'est vrai ! Il sait parler.
They all can talk. They were having a meeting.
Ils savent parler. Ils ont tenu une rיunion.
There's something about puppies.
Au sujet des chiots.
It's one big baby con-spy-racy!
C'est une conspiration de bיbיs !
Timothy Leslie Templeton!
Timothy Leslie Templeton !
We are very disappointed in you.
Tu nous dיחois beaucoup.
- No, we're mad at you! - Exactly, we're mad at you.
- Non, nous sommes fגchיs ! - Fגchיs contre toi.
- Mad? - You need a time-out!
- Fגchיs ? - Il faut t'isoler !
- You're grounded! - Yes, grounded!
- Tu es puni ! - Oui, puni !
- For two... - Three!
- Pour deux... - Trois !
- Three days? - Weeks!
- Trois jours ? - Semaines !
Weeks! Three weeks!
Semaines ! Trois semaines !
For three... evers!
Pour trois... toujours !
Grounded?
Privי de sortie ?
You're gonna stay in this house with your baby brother...
Tu resteras dans cette maison avec ton petit frטre
until you learn to get along.
jusqu'א ce que tu apprennes א t'entendre avec lui.
Great.
Super.
It was my first time behind bars.
C'יtait mon premier sיjour derriטre les barreaux.
The big house.
Au cachot.
The lock-up.
L'enfermement.
Grounded for life.
Puni א vie.
The minutes turned into hours, the hours into days.
Les minutes sont devenues des heures, et les heures, des jours.
Every man has his breaking point.
Tout homme a une limite.
This was mine.
C'יtait la mienne.
Blackbird singing in the dead of night
Un merle chante sous les יtoiles
- Take these broken wings and learn to fly - Hey, that's my song.
- Malgrי tes ailes cassיes - Hי ! C'est ma berceuse.
All your life
Tu dois apprendre א voler Toute ta vie
You were only waiting For this moment to arise
Tu as attendu la chance De t'יlancer dans le firmament
It's okay, little halfling.
ַa va aller, petit enfant-nain.
Perhaps I can be of some assistance.
Je peux peut-ךtre t'aider.
Blackbird singing in the dead of night!
Un merle chante sous les יtoiles !
Pray, take these broken wings and learn to fly!
Malgrי tes ailes cassיes, tu dois apprendre א voler !
Fly, you fools!
Envolez-vous, bךtas !
Thanks, Wizzie.
Merci, le mage.
But it's not the same.
Mais ce n'est pas pareil.
If only I could reach my magical shank.
Si seulement je pouvais atteindre mon canif magique,
I could break us out of this big house.
je m'enfuirais de ce cachot.
Templeton!
Templeton !
Templeton, we have to talk.
Templeton, il faut qu'on parle.
Go away.
Va-t'en.
Blackbird singing in the dead of night
Un merle chante sous les יtoiles
Stop it!
Arrךte de chanter !
That's my song, not yours.
C'est ma berceuse, pas la tienne.
My parents wrote it just for me.
Mes parents l'ont יcrite pour moi.
Really? Your parents are Lennon and McCartney?
Tes parents sont Lennon et McCartney ?
No, Ted and Janice.
Non, Ted et Janice.
You don't even know their names!
Tu ne connais mךme pas leurs noms !
You're just trying to steal them from me.
Tu veux juste me les voler !
You stole everything!
Tu as tout volי !
You're the one who should be in jail!
C'est toi qui devrais ךtre en prison !
Look, it's time we put our differences aside.
ֹcoute, le temps est venu de nous rיconcilier.
Have you been...
As-tu...
No!
Non !
Where's HR when you need them?
Oש sont les Ressources humaines quand on en a besoin ?
Take it.
Prends חa.
I don't want your filthy money.
Je ne veux pas de ton argent sale.
Look, I told you to stay out of my way.
ֹcoute, je t'ai dit de t'יcarter de mon chemin.
I can't! You're in my house.
Je ne peux pas ! Tu es chez moi.
I don't wanna be here...
Je ne souhaite pas rester ici
any more than you want me to be here.
tout comme tu ne veux pas que j'y reste.
Then why are you torturing me?
Alors, pourquoi me tortures-tu ?
The truth is I'm no ordinary baby.
En fait, je ne suis pas un bיbי ordinaire.
Well, no kidding.
Sans blague !
I'm on a mission from above.
J'ai reחu une mission du Ciel.
Are you the Baby Jesus?
Es-tu le petit Jיsus ?
Yes. I'm the Baby Jesus.
Mais oui, je suis le petit Jיsus.
No!
Non !
You see, I'm more middle management for the company.
Vois-tu, je suis cadre intermיdiaire dans l'entreprise.
The company? What company?
L'entreprise ? Quelle entreprise ?
Here.
Tiens.
Take this. It'll explain everything.
Prends חa. ַa explique tout.
What do you want me to do with that?
Que veux-tu que j'en fasse ?
- I want you to suck it. - You suck it!
- Je veux que tu suces. - Fais-le, toi !
No, it's for you to suck.
Non, suce-la.
I'm not sucking that!
Je ne sucerai pas !
- Suck it. - I don't know where it's been!
- Suce. - Imagine les microbes !
It's not where it's been. It's where it will take you.
Tu ignores oש la suce peut t'entraמner.
Don't you wanna know...
Ne veux-tu pas savoir
where babies really come from?
d'oש viennent les bיbיs ?
Binky. Papish. Nuk-Nuk.
Miam-miam. Mouk-mouk.
Boo-Boo. Bo-Bo. Bah-Bah.
Bou-bou. Ba-ba.
Chupie. Hushie-Baby. Tootsie.
Bon-bon. Tיtine.
It goes by many names.
Elle porte de nombreux noms.
But through its power, you will know the truth.
Mais par ses pouvoirs, tu apprendras la vיritי.
Come on, faster!
Allez, plus vite !
Mommy!
Maman !
Where are we?
Oש sommes-nous ?
Welcome to Baby Corp!
Bienvenue א Bיbי et Cie !
No way.
Incroyable !
- Thank you. - What?
- Merci. - Quoi ?
Relax. They can't see us or hear us.
Dיtends-toi. Ils ne nous voient ni ne nous entendent.
- We're, like, virtual and stuff? - Yep.
- On est virtuels, alors ? - Oui.
- You mean they won't feel this? - Nope.
- Ils ne sentiront pas חa ? - Non.
- Or this? - Nada.
- Ou ceci ? - Rien.
Karate!
Du karatי !
Don't embarrass yourself, Templeton. I can still see you.
Ne t'humilie pas, Templeton. Moi, je te vois.
So this is where babies come from?
C'est d'ici que viennent les bיbיs ?
Where'd you think, the cabbage patch?
Tu croyais aux bיbיs trouvיs dans les choux ?
Magic fairies?
Aux fיes ?
No, my parents told me that...
Non, mes parents m'ont dit que...
What?
Quoi ?
No. That's disgusting.
Non, c'est dיgotant.
Yeah, it didn't sound right to me, either.
Oui, je me doutais que c'יtait impossible.
I can't believe my parents didn't tell me about this.
Incroyable que mes parents ne m'aient rien dit.
If people knew where babies really came from, they'd never have one.
Si les gens savaient d'oש viennent les bיbיs, ils n'en auraient pas.
Same thing with hot dogs, by the way.
Pareil pour les hot-dogs.
Going upsies!
On monte, les amis !
So how come I don't remember this place?
Alors, j'ai oubliי cet endroit ?
You did.
Tu t'en souvenais.
But after normal babies get their pacifiers taken away...
Mais une fois qu'on enlטve la suce aux bיbיs,
you forget all about Baby Corp.
ils oublient Bיbי et Cie.
How come you're not normal?
Mais toi, tu n'es pas normal.
A few of us, the best of the best...
Quelques-uns d'entre nous, la crטme de la crטme,
are selected for the...
sommes choisis pour le...
For the ultimate honor.
L'insigne honneur.
Upper management.
La haute direction.
This, Templeton, is where all the action is.
ַa, Templeton, c'est lא que l'action se passe.
Nap time in Sector G.
Dodo dans le Secteur G.
So this whole place is run by babies?
Le complexe est dirigי par des bיbיs ?
Yep.
Oui.
My Dad says, "Those who can, do."
Mon pטre dit : "Les compיtents agissent,
"And those who can't, supervise."
"et les incompיtents dirigent."
Your father is a hippy.
Ton pטre est un hippy.
What happens when you grow up?
Et quand vous grandissez ?
We don't.
On ne grandit jamais.
We drink a super-secret baby formula that keeps us babies forever.
On boit une prיparation secrטte qui nous garde jeunes א jamais.
Back to work! Formula break is over!
ְ vos postes ! La pause-prיparation est terminיe !
We're in a crisis here!
On est en pleine crise !
Don't you know we're in a crisis here?
Vous ne savez pas que c'est la crise ?
Who is that?
Qui est-ce ?
That is my boss. Big Boss Baby.
C'est ma patronne. La "Boss" des bיbיs.
What is she screaming about?
Pourquoi crie-t-elle ?
Well, see this pie chart?
Tu vois ce diagramme circulaire ?
Wow, it looks like a giant pie.
Ouah ! On dirait une tarte gיante !
It represents all the love there is in the world.
ַa reprיsente tout l'amour dans le monde.
- I love pie. - Who doesn't?
- J'adore la tarte. - Normal.
- Apple. - Fine.
- Aux pommes. - Oui.
- No, cherry! - Perfect!
- Non, aux cerises ! - Parfait !
- Not pumpkin. - Okay.
- Pas א la citrouille. - D'accord.
That's a vegetable.
C'est un lיgume.
Point is, the puppies' slice is getting bigger and bigger.
Regarde, la part des chiots augmente sans cesse.
They're stealing all our love!
Ils volent tout notre amour !
Just like you did to me.
Comme tu as volי le mien.
Exactly.
Exactement.
And if this keeps up...
Et si חa continue,
there might not be enough pie left for babies.
il n'y aura plus de tarte pour les bיbיs.
No pie?
Plus de tarte ?
No pie.
Plus de tarte.
So, my mission is to find out what this new puppy is.
Ma mission est de dיcouvrir ce qu'est ce nouveau chiot.
So you're, like, on a spy mission? Cool!
Tu mטnes une mission d'espionnage ? C'est super !
Yes! Cool! And if... When I succeed...
Oui ! C'est super ! Et si... Quand j'aurai rיussi,
I'll become a Baby Corp legend.
je deviendrai une lיgende de Bיbי et Cie.
Like Super Big Boss Baby, Mega Boss Baby...
Super Mיga Bיbי "boss", Mיga Bיbי "boss"...
Seriously Big Boss Baby...
Gigantesque Bיbי "boss"
and him.
et lui.
Now that's a big, fat baby.
Quel gros bיbי joufflu !
No, that's Big Fat Boss Baby.
Non, c'est lui le Grassouillet Bיbי "boss".
This is Super Colossal Big Fat Boss Baby.
Voici Super mיga colossal Bיbי "boss".
He was the youngest Chief Executive Infant in the history of the company.
L'ex-directeur gיnיral le plus jeune de l'histoire de l'entreprise.
Was? What happened to him?
L'ex ? Que lui est-il arrivי ?
Retired, years ago.
Il a pris sa retraite, il y a des annיes.
But I still try and live up to his legend.
Mais je tente d'ךtre digne de sa lיgende.
In every situation, I ask myself...
Dans toute situation, je me demande :
"W-W-S-C-B-F-B-B-D?
"Q-F-S-M-C-B-B ?"
"What Would Super Colossal Big Fat Boss Baby Do?"
"Que ferait Super mיga colossal Bיbי 'boss' ?"
So that's all you get? Your picture on the wall?
C'est tout ce que tu auras ? Ta photo sur le mur ?
Come here!
Suis-moi !
I'll get a promotion.
J'aurai une promotion.
The corner office...
Le bureau du coin,
with my own private potty.
avec mon petit pot personnel.
Wow.
Ouah !
So when you're done, you're coming back here?
Quand tu auras terminי, tu reviendras ici ?
A-S-A-P, T-i-m.
Aussitפt que possible, T-i-m.
I'm not a family man. I belong behind a desk.
Je ne suis pas un homme de famille, mais d'entreprise.
- That's awesome! - I know, right?
- C'est merveilleux ! - N'est-ce pas ?
- Pew pew. - What?
- Paf ! Paf ! - Quoi ?
So help me, I will nail his diaper to the wall!
Je vais lui clouer la couche au mur !
Have we heard anything from that little Boss Baby...
Avons-nous des nouvelles du petit patron
that we sent down to the Templetons?
qui a יtי postי chez les Templeton ?
- I don't know. - You're fired!
- Je ne sais pas. - Tu es virיe !
Oh, no.
Non.
You're all fired!
Vous ךtes tous virיs !
The pet convention is in two days.
La foire des animaux est dans deux jours.
If he doesn't come up with answers...
S'il ne trouve pas de rיponses,
he is fired, retired!
il est virי, forcי א la retraite !
- Gone! - Tour's over.
- Chassי ! - La visite est terminיe.
What was Big Bossy Baby Lady screaming about?
Pourquoi Bיbי "boss" criait-elle ?
She's demanding actual results.
Elle exige des rיsultats concrets.
The pet convention is in two days, and I've got nothing!
La foire des animaux de compagnie approche, et je n'ai rien.
That's her! Don't answer it!
C'est elle ! Ne rיponds pas !
Stress nap!
Dodo d'anxiיtי !
If I don't find out what that new puppy is and fast...
Si je ne dיcouvre pas trטs vite le nouveau produit,
not only will I not get that promotion...
je n'aurai pas ma promotion et...
I could get fired!
je risque d'ךtre virי !
Hey, relax.
Calme-toi.
I'm sure there's other cool jobs for babies, right?
Il y a srement d'autres emplois pour les bיbיs ?
Meanwhile, two days goes by like that.
Deux jours, חa file א la vitesse de l'יclair.
You better start packing.
Commence א faire tes valises.
What?
Quoi ?
You don't get it, Templeton.
Tu ne piges pas, Templeton.
If I'm fired, they'll take away my formula.
Si je suis virי, je n'aurai plus de prיparation.
I will turn into a normal baby...
Je me transformerai en bיbי ordinaire
and live here forever with you.
et devrai vivre ici avec vous א jamais.
- No! - Yes!
- Non ! - Oui !
And I promise you this...
Et je te le promets...
Every morning you wake up...
Chaque matin, א ton rיveil,
I'll be there.
je serai lא.
Every night, at dinner...
Chaque soir, au souper,
Every birthday party...
ְ chaque anniversaire,
I'll be there.
je serai lא.
Every Christmas!
ְ chaque Noכl !
I'll be there
Je serai lא
Year after year after year.
Annיe aprטs annיe.
We will grow old together.
Nous grandirons ensemble.
You and I...
Toi et moi
will be brothers.
serons des frטres.
Always.
Pour toujours.
- No. No, this is terrible! - I know.
- Non, c'est affreux ! - Je le sais.
- This can't be happening. - But it is!
- ַa ne se peut pas. - C'est la vיritי !
- You can't stay here! - I can't!
- Tu dois partir ! - Je sais !
- Don't panic! - But it feels right!
- Pas de panique ! - Mais חa s'impose !
I know, but we have to fix this.
Je le sais, mais nous devons rיgler חa.
We have to make sure you don't get fired.
On fera tout pour ne pas que tu sois virי.
We?
"On" ?
We.
On.
I will help you...
Je vais t'aider
but just to get rid of you.
juste pour me dיbarrasser de toi.
Deal?
Marchי conclu ?
Deal.
Marchי conclu.
Here's to never seeing you again.
Vivement nos adieux !
Back at ya, baby.
Bien d'accord, bיbי.
Now let's get to work.
Mettons-nous au travail.
Come on, come on, come on.
Allez, allez, allez.
Slice!
Crochet extיrieur !
No, no.
Non, non.
There's nothing here about a new puppy.
Il n'y a rien ici sur un nouveau chiot.
Aren't you gonna do any work?
Tu ne fais rien ?
I'm very busy delegating.
Je m'efforce de dיlיguer.
He drains it!
Coup roulי !
So once we find the file on the new puppy...
Quand on aura trouvי le dossier sur le chiot,
what do we do then?
qu'allons-nous faire ?
Send in the baby ninjas?
Faire appel aux ninjas bיbיs ?
Even better.
Encore mieux que חa.
I'm going to write the perfect memo.
J'יcrirai une note de service יloquente.
- Boom!
- Boum !
Wait. What's a memo?
Attends. C'est quoi, une note de service ?
A memo is something you write to give people information.
C'est une note qui transmet des informations.
That's your plan? You're gonna write a book report?
C'est חa, ton plan ? Une dissertation ?
That's so boring.
C'est d'un ennui mortel.
No, Templeton.
Non, Templeton.
Memos are for important things.
Les notes servent des buts nobles.
A memo can bring people together.
Elles rassemblent la population.
A memo can be a call to arms...
Une note peut ךtre un appel aux armes,
a manifesto, a poem.
un manifeste, un poטme.
A memo can change the world.
Une note de service peut changer le monde.
Wow! When you explain it like that...
Ouah ! Quand tu l'expliques comme חa,
it still sounds boring.
c'est tout aussi assommant.
You'll learn, kid.
Tu apprendras, mon petit.
You'll learn.
Tu apprendras.
Wait a second. This is it!
Attends un peu. Voilא !
What? What is it?
Quoi ? Qu'est-ce que c'est ?
Check this out. Take Your Kid to Work Day.
Regarde חa. C'est le Jour des enfants au travail.
People take children to a place of business? Why?
Les gens emmטnent leurs enfants au travail ? Pourquoi ?
Because it's awesome!
Parce que c'est fantastique !
It's disgusting.
C'est dיgotant.
Don't you see? We can get inside Puppy Co...
Ne vois-tu pas ? On peut s'introduire lא
and find out what the new puppy is!
et dיcouvrir la nature du chiot !
What's the point?
ַa sert א quoi ?
You're grounded.
Tu es privי de sortie.
Your parents aren't going to take us anywhere.
Tes parents ne nous emmטneront nulle part.
You're right. They think we hate each other.
Tu as raison. Ils croient qu'on se dיteste.
Hate is a strong word.
"Dיtester", le mot est fort.
It's the right word, but still.
C'est le mot juste, mais quand mךme.
We have to convince them that we're actual brothers.
Il faut les convaincre qu'on est des frטres.
Right.
Oui.
That we...
Qu'on est unis par l'a...
Loathe?
La haine ?
No.
Non.
Like!
L'amitiי !
No. That we...
Non, par l'am...
La, la, la...
La, la, la...
Le, Le, Le...
Le, le, le...
No.
Non.
No way. No. You don't mean...
Pas question. Non. Tu ne veux pas dire...
Love each other.
Unis par l'amour.
I just threw up a noodle and swallowed it.
Je viens de dיgueuler une nouille pour l'avaler.
- Here comes the choo-choo train! - No.
- Le petit train arrive ! - Non.
- Choo, choo, chugga, chugga. - No choo-choo!
- Tchou-tchou. - Non, pas חa !
Hold the train! No! It looks like it's already been eaten!
Retiens le train ! Non ! On dirait que c'est prיmגchי !
Who's there? I got a racket!
Qui va lא ? Je suis armי !
What's going on in here?
Que se passe-t-il ici ?
I'm just feeding the baby.
Je nourris le bיbי.
They're watching.
Ils nous regardent.
Choo-choo.
Tchou-tchou.
Okay.
D'accord.
Choo-choo on that.
Gobe חa, cuistot.
I don't wear nautical. It's not even Friday!
Je ne m'habille pas en matelot. On n'est mךme pas vendredi !
Come on, you're putting this thing on!
Allez, mets חa !
You gonna make me? You can't make me, punk.
Tu ne peux pas m'y forcer, espטce de vaurien.
- What have you done to me? - Stop!
- Que m'as-tu fait ? - Arrךte !
- Get back here! - No!
- Reviens ici ! - Non !
No way.
Pas question.
Come on!
Allez !
Tim, what are you doing in here?
Tim, que fais-tu ?
Oh, no.
Non.
Hey, what's all the racket?
C'est quoi, tout ce tapage ?
Isn't he adorable?
N'est-il pas adorable ?
I've got one for you, too! Ahoy, matey!
J'en ai un pour toi aussi ! Ohי, matelot !
What?
Quoi ?
Bummer.
Dommage.
Smile!
Souriez !
Smile for the camera.
Souris א la camיra.
It makes me feel weak.
Je me sens faible.
- Who's ticklish? - It doesn't work on me.
- Es-tu chatouilleux ? - Pas du tout.
- Here? - I'm dead down there.
- Ici ? - Aucune sensation.
Come on, everyone has a tickle spot.
Allez, on a tous un point faible.
"'I don't think I'll fit,' said Gretel."
"'C'est trop exigu pour moi', dit Gretel."
Come here, look at this.
Viens, regarde חa.
"'I could get in myself.'
"'Je pourrais y entrer moi-mךme.'
"And then, Hansel and Gretel...
"C'est alors que Hansel et Gretel
"pushed the wicked old woman into the oven.
"poussטrent la vieillarde dans le four.
"And the godless witch was miserably burnt to death."
"Et la mיchante sorciטre fut brlיe vive."
Let me get this straight.
Est-ce que j'ai bien compris ?
The story is about cannibalism and burning people alive.
C'est un conte sur le cannibalisme et la mort par le feu ?
Yeah.
Oui.
No wonder kids are so messed up!
Pas יtonnant que les enfants soient si troublיs !
Getting along is exhausting.
La bonne entente, c'est יpuisant.
Back at ya, Tim.
Tu as raison, Tim.
You should have seen your face in that picture.
Tu aurais d voir ton air sur la photo.
You were all...
Tu יtais tout...
I'm not used to being tickled.
On ne me chatouille pas souvent.
Once at a corporate retreat. But those things always get weird.
Une fois, א une rיunion champךtre, mais חa dיgיnטre vite.
What? You've never been tickled? What about your parents?
Quoi ? Pas de chatouilles ? Et tes parents, alors ?
I'm sorry. I forgot.
Je regrette, j'avais oubliי.
You didn't have parents, did you?
Tu n'as pas eu de parents, hein ?
Tim, I may look like a baby...
Tim, j'ai peut-ךtre l'air d'un bיbי,
but I was born all grown up.
mais je suis nי adulte.
I can't even imagine not being a kid.
Je ne peux pas m'imaginer l'גge adulte.
You missed out on your whole childhood?
Tu n'as pas eu d'enfance ?
You never had someone to love you?
N'as-tu pas eu quelqu'un pour t'aimer ?
You can't miss what you never had.
Ce qu'on n'a pas connu ne nous manque pas.
Wake up, little halflings!
Debout, petits enfants-nains !
Hey, Tim. Wake up, buddy.
Tim. Debout, mon grand.
- What? - Rise and shine!
- Quoi ? - Allez, rיveille-toi !
Is something wrong? Am I fired?
Un problטme ? Je suis virי ?
No, you're late for work.
Tu es en retard pour le travail.
What?
Quoi ?
It's Take Your Kid to Work Day! And you're the kid.
C'est le Jour des enfants au travail, donc, toi.
You're officially un-grounded.
Ta punition est levיe officiellement.
- Really? - Really.
- C'est vrai ? - C'est vrai.
Can the baby come, too?
Le bיbי peut-il venir aussi ?
I don't see why not.
Pourquoi pas ?
Yes! Yes, yes, yes!
Oui ! Oui, oui, oui !
Yeah!
Ouais !
I wish I was that excited for work.
J'envie son enthousiasme pour le bureau.
Look, it's my spatula.
Regarde, c'est ma spatule.
Yeah, baby.
Oui, bיbי.
All right, gentlemen. Welcome to Puppy Co.
Bon, messieurs. Bienvenue א Chiot et Cie.
Wow! This is awesome!
Ouah ! C'est gיnial !
And Tim, look!
Tim, regarde !
They have a puppy pool and everything!
Ils ont une piscine א chiots et tout !
Isn't that sanitary?
C'est hygiיnique ?
Hey, bud, you wanna get a picture with Puppy Co Pete?
Mon grand, veux-tu une photo avec la mascotte Pete ?
No, thanks. It's probably too scary for the baby.
Non merci. ַa risque de faire peur au bיbי.
Nice call.
Bien vu.
Your dad and I have some work to do.
Ton pטre et moi avons du travail א faire.
You wanna come up to the office and hang out with us?
Tu veux nous accompagner au bureau ?
We'll stick your brother in the Puppy Zone...
Nous laisserons ton frטre ici
while we have a little Tim time.
pour nous consacrer א Tim.
Tim time?
ְ Tim ?
Dad and I know we haven't been able to do as much with you as we used to.
Papa et moi n'avons pas fait autant d'activitיs avec toi qu'avant.
So, what do you say?
Alors, qu'en dis-tu ?
No, thanks.
Non merci.
I'd rather spend time with the baby.
Je prיfטre passer du temps avec le bיbי.
- So cute. - That's so sweet.
- Trטs mignon ! - Trטs gentil !
Way to keep your eyes on the prize, Templeton.
Tu n'oublies pas notre mission, bravo.
We find out what the new puppy is, and I go home.
Quand on trouvera le nouveau chiot, je rentrerai chez moi.
You guys stay in the Puppy Zone, okay?
Restez dans la zone des chiots, d'accord ?
Okay, bye!
D'accord, au revoir !
That's where we'll find the secret file on the new puppy.
C'est lא que nous trouverons le dossier secret.
We'll never get through that door.
On ne passera jamais cette porte.
No, not that door.
Pas cette porte-lא.
The doggy door.
La porte des chiots.
But how do we get past the guard?
Mais comment dיjouer le garde ?
No, no, no. No way.
Non, non, non. Pas question.
No!
Non !
Itchy, plushy, puppy pants!
Le pantalon de toutou me pique !
What a cute, little pup...
Quel chiot adorable...
Ow!
Ouille !
Yay!
Hourra !
Kids.
Les enfants.
Get down.
Baisse-toi.
All the way down.
ְ quatre pattes.
I've never been so humiliated in all my life.
Je n'ai jamais יtי aussi humiliי de ma vie.
Arf!
Ouf !
Hey!
Hי !
Fetch!
Allez chercher !
What am I doing?
Qu'est-ce que je fais ?
Oh, no!
Non !
Yes!
Oui !
What a good boy.
Bon toutou.
No. No biting.
Non. On ne mord pas.
Timothy Templeton, office ninja.
Timothy Templeton, ninja de bureau.
- Over here. - What is it?
- Par ici. - Qu'est-ce que c'est ?
It's gotta be in here.
Ce doit ךtre lא-dedans.
It's begging us to go in.
Elle nous appelle א entrer.
Wow.
Ouah !
That's a lot of paperwork.
Il y a beaucoup de paperasse.
I thought puppies shredded everything.
Je croyais que les chiots dיchiraient tout.
This is getting creepy.
ַa fait peur.
I've come for your soul.
Je vais m'emparer de ton גme.
Cut it out!
Arrךte !
Wait!
Attends !
That's it!
Le voilא !
The file!
Le dossier !
See! I was right.
Tu vois ! J'avais raison.
No. I've seen this before somewhere.
Non, j'ai dיjא vu חa quelque part.
We've gotta find something to replace it with.
Il faut le remplacer par quelque chose.
You're right. Like another file.
Tu as raison. Par un autre dossier.
Yes! A file with the same weight.
Oui ! Un fichier du mךme poids.
So it can be placed in the exact same position.
ְ placer dans la mךme position.
- With the exact same weight. - You already said that.
- Du mךme poids. - Tu l'as dיjא dit.
I know I said it. Hey, you hit me twice.
Je le sais. Tu m'as frappי deux fois.
Make it a third time. Wait!
Allons-y une troisiטme fois. Attends !
I think I've seen one here.
Je crois en avoir vu un.
Smead manila, pressboard edges.
Papier Manille, א couverture cartonnיe.
About 50 ounces. No, 49.
1,42 kilo. Non, 1,41.
Try this one.
Essaie celui-ci.
Wait!
Attends !
Now it's perfect.
Lא, c'est parfait.
Yes!
Oui !
I feel like we should run.
Je pense qu'on devrait s'enfuir.
I know, but it's just so mesmerizing.
Je sais, mais c'est envotant.
I kind of wanna see how it ends.
Je veux voir comment חa va finir.
Yeah, me too.
Oui, moi aussi.
Well, that didn't end well.
ַa s'est mal fini.
What?
Quoi ?
What the...?
Mais que...
Thanks for dropping in, kids.
Merci d'ךtre venus faire un tour.
Francis Francis?
Francis Francis ?
I see you've met my big brother, Eugene.
Vous avez rencontrי mon grand frטre, Eugene.
A man of few words.
Un homme peu loquace.
None, in fact.
Il ne parle pas, en fait.
Can you put your head back on, please?
Pourriez-vous remettre votre tךte, s'il vous plaמt ?
What is all this?
Qu'est-ce que c'est ?
Surprise!
Surprise !
A Baby Corp binky? Where did you get that?
Une suce de Bיbי et Cie ? Oש avez-vous trouvי חa ?
You don't recognize me?
Tu ne me reconnais pas ?
Perhaps from my youth!
De mon enfance, peut-ךtre !
Super Colossal Big Fat Boss Baby?
Super mיga colossal Bיbי "boss" ?
He is him? And him is you?
C'est lui ? Et lui, c'est toi ?
Except older and wrinklier.
Mais plus vieux et plus ridי.
That's not right.
Trטs moche.
No. You were my hero!
Non. Tu יtais mon hיros !
How did you end up here?
Comment t'es-tu retrouvי ici ?
You know what I do to little kids who ask lots of questions about me?
Tu sais ce que je fais aux enfants qui me harcטlent de questions ?
Eugene!
Eugene !
I read them my story.
Je leur lis mon histoire.
And, I baked cookies!
Et j'ai fait des biscuits !
Eugene, my chair.
Eugene, mon fauteuil.
Now, it all started at Baby Corp...
Tout a commencי א Bיbי et Cie
a long, long time ago.
il y a de cela fort longtemps.
I was a hotshot executive...
Comme cadre, j'avais le vent en poupe
headed straight to the top.
et je visais les plus hauts sommets.
Everyone loved me.
Tout le monde m'aimait.
They gave me a promotion, the corner office...
J'ai יtי promu et j'ai hיritי du grand bureau,
my very own...
de mon propre...
Personal potty?
Petit pot ?
I had it all.
J'avais tout ce qu'on peut dיsirer.
But then one day...
Mais un jour,
I made a terrible discovery.
j'ai fait une terrible dיcouverte.
I was getting old.
Je vieillissais.
The formula wasn't working anymore.
La prיparation lactיe ne fonctionnait plus.
It turns out I was lactose intolerant.
En fait, j'יtais intolיrant au lactose.
- No! - Yes!
- Non ! - Oui !
I got called in to see the board of directors.
Les administrateurs m'ont convoquי.
Who are the boring directors?
Qui sont les adminis-menteurs ?
The biggest baby bosses of them all.
Les grands patrons des bיbיs patrons.
I thought they loved me.
Je croyais qu'ils m'aimaient.
But they replaced me with someone new.
Mais ils m'ont trouvי un remplaחant.
Someone younger.
Une jeune.
That's horrible.
C'est horrible.
All of a sudden, she got all the love...
Tout א coup, on lui accordait tout l'amour
all the attention.
et toute l'attention.
You know how that feels, don't you, Tim?
Tu sais ce que c'est, Tim ?
It hurts, doesn't it?
C'est blessant, non ?
Yeah. It does.
Oui, c'est vrai.
And then what happened?
Qu'est-il arrivי ensuite ?
Well...
Eh bien...
They fired me!
Ils m'ont virי !
And took away my special formula.
Et ils ont volי ma prיparation spיciale.
Then they sent me down to live with a...
Ensuite, ils m'ont envoyי vivre
- family! - Oh, Francis, no!
- dans une famille ! - Francis, non !
Baby Corp betrayed me!
Bיbי et Cie m'a trahi !
And I'm finally going to get revenge...
Je vais enfin me venger avec...
with the Forever Puppy.
le Chiot יternel.
- Huh? - That's it?
- Hein ? - C'est tout ?
No, no.
Non, non.
Imagine a puppy that never grows up.
Imaginez un chiot qui ne grandit pas.
A puppy that stays a puppy forever.
Un chiot qui reste bיbי א jamais.
Once I launch my Forever Puppies to every corner of the world...
Quand j'aurai lancי mes Chiots יternels aux quatre coins du globe,
they'll be so adorable...
ils seront si adorables...
How cute!
Comme c'est mignon !
...no one will ever want a baby ever, ever again.
... que personne ne voudra plus jamais de bיbי.
The end of Baby Corp!
Ce sera la fin de Bיbי et Cie !
Please.
Franchement !
A puppy that never grows up? That's impossible!
Un chiot qui ne grandit pas ? C'est impossible !
Isn't it?
Pas vrai ?
It was, until you brought me the key ingredient.
Ce l'יtait jusqu'א ce que tu m'apportes l'ingrיdient clי.
My secret formula.
Ma prיparation secrטte.
It's mine! It's mine!
C'est pour moi !
It's all mine.
Elle est toute א moi.
No!
Non !
You brought me the very thing I needed to destroy Baby Corp.
Tu m'as apportי ce dont j'avais besoin pour dיtruire Bיbי et Cie.
- No! - Yes!
- Non ! - Oui !
You walked right into my trap!
Tu es tombי dans mon piטge !
- You'll never get away with this! - Yeah, not if we...
- ַa ne marchera pas ! - Oui, pas si on...
What? Tell?
Quoi ? On me dיnonce ?
Who are you gonna tell, Tim? Your parents?
Me dיnoncer א qui, Tim ? ְ tes parents ?
Where are the boys?
Oש sont les garחons ?
I told them to stay in the Puppy Zone.
Je leur ai dit de rester ici.
I'm taking them both with me to Las Vegas.
Je les emmטne tous les deux א Las Vegas.
So stay out of my way.
Hors de mon chemin.
I'd hate for them to get terminated.
Ce serait dommage que le couperet tombe pour eux.
They'd never leave us alone.
Ils ne nous laisseront pas seuls.
Oh, really?
Vraiment ?
Wait until they meet Puppy Co's certified...
Attends qu'ils rencontrent l'experte
in-house childcare expert.
patentיe du gardiennage א domicile.
Oh, no.
Non.
- Don't be nervous, buddy. - It's only overnight.
- Ne t'inquiטte pas. - Ce n'est qu'une nuit.
We'll be back before you know it.
On sera de retour en moins de deux.
Besides, you boys are in great hands.
En plus, vous ךtes en bonnes mains.
That's right!
C'est vrai !
Eugenia is practically perfect in every way.
Eugenia est presque parfaite.
No.
Non.
Please don't go with him. Francis Francis is trying to...
Ne le suivez pas, je vous en prie. Francis Francis tente...
Believe me...
Croyez-moi,
Eugenia won't take her eyes off your children.
Eugenia ne quittera pas vos enfants des yeux.
Not for one second.
Pas un seul instant.
That's very reassuring.
ַa me rassure.
Now you see them.
Vous les voyez.
And now, you don't.
Vous ne les voyez plus.
Too-da-loo!
Tourlou !
To the airport!
En route vers l'aיroport !
It's over. I'm through.
C'est sans espoir. Je suis cuit.
What do we do, Templeton?
Que faire, Templeton ?
What do we do?
Que faire ?
We have to get to the airport and stop Francis Francis...
Nous rendre א l'aיroport et arrךter Francis Francis
before the plane takes off!
avant que l'avion dיcolle !
Yes! But how do we get past Scary Poppins down there?
Oui ! Mais comment contourner Maligne Poppins en bas ?
Okay. There must be something we can do.
Il doit bien y avoir un moyen.
Hey, it's not that bad.
Hי ! Tout n'est pas dיsespיrי.
Are you okay?
Est-ce que חa va ?
What's the matter with you?
Qu'est-ce qui te prend ?
Don't look at me!
Ne me regarde pas !
Oh, no!
Non !
Without that formula, I turn into a normal baby.
Sans prיparation, je tomberai en enfance.
You know, goo-goo, Ga-ga. The whole bit!
Tu sais, gougou, gaga et tout חa !
Oh, no!
Non !
Gross!
C'est dיgotant !
I'm a ticking baby time bomb!
Je suis un bיbי-bombe prךt א exploser !
I'm going to turn into a puking, pooping, helpless baby!
Je vais me transformer en bיbי vulnיrable qui vomit et qui fait caca !
Wait a second. That gives me an idea.
Attends. ַa me donne une idיe.
What? What is it?
Quoi ? Laquelle ?
I've been through a lot of babysitters...
J'ai eu de nombreuses gardiennes,
and they all fear one thing.
et elles craignent toutes la mךme chose.
Now, ladies, the secret to deep fried butter...
Mesdames, le secret d'un beurre grillי א la perfection,
is a healthy dab of margarine.
c'est un doigt de belle margarine.
Hey, Mr. Lady Man!
Hי, monsieur la Madame !
The baby. I think he's sick!
Le bיbי. Je pense qu'il est malade !
You gotta do something!
Vous devez faire quelque chose !
Oh, the horror!
Quelle horreur !
- Templeton! - Delicious!
- Templeton ! - C'est dיlicieux !
Gross! It got in your mouth!
Dיgueulasse ! Vous en avez avalי !
It got in my mouth, too!
Et moi aussi !
I think I'm gonna be sick!
J'ai mal au cur !
Swirly!
Tourbillon de cuvette !
There's only an hour before the plane takes off.
L'avion dיcolle dans une heure.
Let's take the bike.
Allons-y א bicyclette.
The bike?
ְ bicyclette ?
I don't know.
Je ne suis pas sr.
Let's move!
Vite !
- Okay, but wait right here! - What?
- Oui, mais attends ici ! - Quoi ?
Where are you going? Templeton!
Oש t'en vas-tu ? Templeton !
Always wear a helmet.
Le casque est indispensable.
Too-da-loo, toilet head!
Tourlou, tךte de cuvette !
You'll never catch us!
Vous ne nous attraperez jamais !
Staci!
Staci !
Staci, come in!
Staci, rיponds !
- Is that you, boss? - Code red!
- C'est vous, patron ? - Code rouge !
I'm being chased by a killer babysitter! Gather the team!
Nounou assassine א mes trousses ! Appelle la bande !
On it, boss.
Je m'en occupe, patron.
- Hello!
- Bonjour !
- Code red.
- Code rouge !
Got it!
Entendu !
We got a code red. Repeat...
Code rouge ! Je rיpטte...
We got a code red!
Code rouge enclenchי !
What are you doing, Templeton? Go, go!
Qu'attends-tu, Templeton ? Allez !
But that's jaywalking!
- Pas le droit de griller le feu ! - Tiens, pour la contravention.
Go!
Vas-y !
I think we lost him!
Je crois qu'on l'a semי !
Oh, no, we didn't!
Non, pas du tout !
Flower power!
C'est babacool !
Pow, pow, pow!
Paf, paf, paf !
That's my boy!
Je le reconnais bien lא !
Poppy!
Paf-pouf !
Run, run, run.
Cours, cours.
Uh-oh.
Oh, oh !
Tim, you've gotta go faster!
Tim, tu dois accיlיrer !
I can't do it!
Je ne peux pas !
You can.
Tu en es capable.
You've got it in you, Templeton. Now, eyes ahead.
Je le sais, Templeton. Regarde droit devant toi.
I said eyes ahead, son!
J'ai dit "droit devant" !
Buttocks up! Now pedal like you mean it!
Hue ! Pיdale pour ta vie !
Either you run the day, or the day runs you.
Soit tu mטnes le convoi, soit le convoi t'יcrase.
Good!
Trטs bien !
Uh-oh!
Oh, oh !
My training wheels! I can't ride without training wheels!
Mes stabilisateurs ! Je ne peux pas rouler sans eux !
Whether you think you can or you think you can't, you're right!
Que tu y croies ou pas, tu as raison !
What are you talking about?
Qu'est-ce que tu racontes ?
The path to success is not a straight line, Templeton...
La voie vers le succטs n'est pas une droite ligne,
but rather a wild ride...
c'est un voyage chaotique,
like a ship at sea.
comme sur un bateau en mer.
And you're a sea captain...
Et tu es un commandant de navire
taming a turbulent ocean!
qui affronte un ocיan dיchaמnי !
I'm a sea captain, taming the ocean!
Je suis un commandant
Good!
Trטs bien !
Tree! I'm gonna hit it!
Je vais foncer sur l'arbre !
Aim for failure, and you'll always succeed.
Quand on vise l'יchec, c'est le succטs assurי.
- What? - Aim away from failure!
- Quoi ? - Ne vise pas l'יchec !
I'm doing it. I'm doing it!
J'y arrive. J'y arrive !
Once success is a habit...
Une fois qu'on rיussit,
then it's all downhill.
c'est la chute annoncיe.
Look!
Regarde !
There they are! Mom, Dad!
Les voilא ! Maman, papa !
- Train! - Choo-choo!
- Un train ! - Tchou-tchou !
Stop!
Arrךte !
What are you doing?
Qu'est-ce que tu fais ?
- We're gonna make it. - But I don't have a quote for this!
- On traverse. - Mais je n'ai rien א citer !
You did it!
Tu as rיussi !
No! We did it.
Non ! On a rיussi.
And all without your training wheels.
Et sans tes stabilisateurs.
Coming through!
Laissez-nous passer !
Baby on board!
Bיbי א bord !
Hang on to your diaper!
Accroche bien ta couche !
Duck and cover!
Mets-toi א l'abri !
Hold it, buddy!
Un instant, l'ami !
I'm gonna need a strip search on two.
Fouille א nu א la deuxiטme porte.
There they are! Mom, Dad!
Les voilא ! Maman, papa !
Hey, not so fast!
Hי ! Pas si vite que חa !
Oh, no.
Non.
Templeton!
Templeton !
- Hey! - Sorry!
- Hי ! - Pardon !
Hey, where'd you go?
Oש es-tu passי ?
Oh, no!
Non !
Not again!
Pas encore !
Not now!
Pas maintenant !
What the...?
Qu'est-ce que...
No, no, no!
Non, non, non !
Come on!
Allez !
I think I ate $1.75.
Je pense que j'ai avalי 1,75 $.
Excuse me, coming through! Mom, Dad!
Pardon, je veux passer ! Maman ! Papa !
Hurry now! Move!
Dיpךchez-vous, allez !
We don't wanna miss our flight!
Ne ratons pas ce vol !
- No! - I warned you!
- Non ! - Je t'avais mis en garde !
Wait!
Attendez !
- No! - No.
- Non ! - Non.
Mom, Dad! Stop!
Maman, papa ! Arrךtez !
No!
Non !
No, no, no.
Non, non, non.
They're gone.
Ils sont partis.
I failed.
J'ai יchouי.
I would've gotten to my parents if I didn't have to go back for you!
Je serais arrivי א temps si je n'יtais pas allי te chercher !
What? We would have been here in plenty of time...
Quoi ? On serait arrivיs א temps si tu savais pיdaler normalement !
We're never going to stop the launch on time.
On ne pourra pas arrךter le dיvoilement א temps.
Who cares? My parents are in danger.
Tant pis. Mes parents sont en danger.
I care! Baby Corp is going to go out of business.
C'est important ! Bיbי et Cie va faire faillite.
That's all you ever talk about.
Tu ne parles que de חa.
You don't even know what it's like to be part of a family.
Tu ne sais mךme pas ce qu'est une famille.
And you don't know what it's like to have a job!
Et tu ignores ce qu'est le travail !
You don't know anything about hugs, or bedtime stories, or special songs!
Tu ne connais rien aux cגlins, aux contes ou aux berceuses familiales !
Oh, please! Stop acting like a baby.
S'il te plaמt, arrךte de te conduire comme un bיbי.
You're a baby!
Tu es un bיbי !
You take that back.
Ravale tes paroles.
My life was perfect until you showed up!
Ma vie יtait parfaite avant toi !
Believe me, kid, the feeling is mutual. I wish I'd never met you!
Je pense la mךme chose. J'aurais mieux aimי ne pas te connaמtre !
I wish you'd never been born!
Si seulement tu n'יtais pas nי !
Where are you going?
Oש t'en vas-tu ?
Fine!
Parfait !
Blackbird singing in the dead of night
Un merle chante sous les יtoiles
Take these broken wings and learn to fly
Malgrי tes ailes cassיes Tu dois apprendre א voler
All your life
Toute ta vie
You were only waiting For this moment to arise
Tu as attendu la chance De t'יlancer dans le firmament
Would Timothy Templeton please pick up the white courtesy phone?
On demande א Timothy Templeton de rיpondre au tיlיphone blanc.
Timothy Leslie Templeton, please pick up the white courtesy phone.
Timothy Leslie Templeton, veuillez rיpondre au tיlיphone blanc.
Leslie.
Leslie.
Hello?
Allפ !
It's me. Don't hang up, Tim!
C'est moi. Ne raccroche pas, Tim !
Tim, I wasn't born. I was hired.
Tim, je ne suis pas nי. On m'a engagי.
What do you mean?
Que veux-tu dire ?
Baby Corp is the only home I've ever known.
Bיbי et Cie est le seul foyer que je connais.
So you're right. I don't know what it's like...
Tu as raison. J'ignore ce qu'est
to be part of a family.
la vie de famille.
But I do care.
Mais je sais que c'est important.
You do?
C'est vrai ?
Yeah.
Ouais.
And the only way to save both is to stop Francis Francis.
Le seul moyen de nous sauver, c'est d'arrךter Francis Francis.
Yeah.
Ouais.
I can't do this without you, Tim.
Je n'y arriverai pas sans toi, Tim.
I need you.
J'ai besoin de toi.
- I guess we do make a pretty good team. - No.
- On fait une bonne יquipe, on dirait. - Non.
Literally, I can't reach the door knobs.
Je ne peux pas atteindre les poignיes.
Oh, right.
C'est vrai.
Don't worry, Tim.
Ne t'inquiטte pas, Tim.
We're gonna save your parents.
On va sauver tes parents.
And your company.
Et ton entreprise.
But how do we get to Vegas now?
Mais comment nous rendre א Las Vegas ?
We're gonna need a miracle.
Il nous faut un miracle.
Follow that Elvis!
Suis cet Elvis !
Why?
Pourquoi ?
Where there's Elvis, there's Vegas!
Les Elvis se retrouvent tous א Las Vegas !
There's another one!
Il y en a un autre !
And another one!
Et un autre !
Elvises everywhere!
Il y a des Elvis partout !
Tim, there's our flight!
Tim, c'est notre vol !
And there goes our ticket!
Et voici notre billet d'avion !
Hey! Don't be cruel!
Hי ! Ne sois pas cruel !
Sorry!
Pardon !
- Well, thank you! - Oh, baby!
- Eh bien, merci ! - Bיbי !
Well, thank you very much.
Merci beaucoup.
Hello.
Bonsoir.
Hi.
Salut.
Ticket please.
Billet, s'il vous plaמt ?
One moment.
Un instant.
It's been stolen!
On m'a volי mon identitי.
Impersonating an Elvis impersonator?
Un faux imitateur d'Elvis aurait pris ta place ?
Get him!
Attrapez-le !
Humina, humina, humina.
Oh mon Dieu, oh mon Dieu, oh mon Dieu !
Stop!
Arrךtez !
The ghost of Elvis!
Le fantפme d'Elvis !
We gotta find seats!
Trouvons des siטges !
Come on, this way!
Viens, par ici !
What is this place?
On est oש ici ?
This, Templeton, is first class.
ַa, Templeton, c'est la premiטre classe.
Why is it empty?
Pourquoi est-elle vide ?
No one can afford it.
Les billets sont trop chers.
That's what makes it so wonderful.
C'est pour חa que c'est aussi gיnial.
Hello! This is Captain Ross.
Bonjour ! Ici le commandant Ross.
Ladies and gentlemen, and those in coach...
Chers passagers et la classe ordinaire,
please fasten your seat belts. We're about to take off.
veuillez attacher votre ceinture. Nous allons dיcoller.
What's the matter, Templeton?
Que se passe-t-il, Templeton ?
My parents always hold my hand during takeoff.
Mes parents me tiennent la main durant le dיcollage.
Boy, the stocks are crazy today.
Bon sang, le marchי est instable en diable.
Ladies and gentlemen, Captain Ross again.
Rebonjour, ici le commandant Ross.
As you can see, I've switched off the seat belt sign.
J'ai יteint le signal de la ceinture.
What are you two boys doing up here?
Que faites-vous ici ?
We're Captain Ross's kids.
On est les enfants du commandant Ross.
He told us to sit here.
Il nous a dit de nous asseoir ici.
Well, can I get you special guys anything?
Je vous offre quelque chose א votre got ?
Anything?
ְ notre got ?
Anything.
ְ votre got.
Aye! All right, Francis Francis.
Grrr ! Bon, Francis Francis.
This will teach you to kidnap the parents of One-Eyed Tim.
ַa t'apprendra א enlever les parents de l'abominable Tim.
Oh, please. If only it were that easy.
Franchement. Comme si c'יtait aussi facile !
What's your plan?
Quel est ton plan ?
You're not gonna write a memo, are you?
Pas une note, j'espטre ?
No.
Non.
Come on. You said you never really had a childhood, right?
Allez. Tu as avouי ne pas avoir eu d'enfance.
Why don't you give it a try?
Pourquoi ne pas jouer un peu ?
- No, I can't. - It's fun!
- Je ne peux pas. - C'est amusant !
Here, let's get you into character.
Allez, rentre dans ton personnage.
I don't know. I feel silly!
Pas sr. J'ai l'air ridicule !
Go on! Say something mean to him.
Allez ! Dis-lui quelque chose de mיchant.
All right, all right, all right.
D'accord, d'accord.
So, you went to a community college, is it?
Tu as frיquentי un collטge communautaire, hein ?
I don't know.
Je ne sais pas.
Keep going!
Continue !
And you have the guts to ask me for a bonus, now?
Et tu as le culot de me demander une prime ?
See!
Tu vois !
Now you're getting into it.
Tu commences א l'avoir.
Huh?
Hein ?
Well, blow me down.
Je n'en reviens pas.
Your exit interview is over!
Ton entretien d'adieu est terminי !
That was pretty good.
C'יtait pas mal bon.
Who was that guy anyway?
Qui יtait-il, au juste ?
- The captain! - What?
- Le capitaine ! - Quoi ?
En garde!
En garde !
Heave!
Halez !
Ho!
Oh !
Thar she blows!
ַa souffle !
Watch your stern!
Attention א la poupe !
- Aye! - Dodge, parry, and thrust!
- ְ vos ordres ! - Esquivez, parez et chargez !
Sounds like a heck of a law firm!
On dirait une corrida !
Nice try! Heads up!
Belle tentative ! Prיparez-vous !
You're fired!
Tu es virי !
And here's your severance package. Ha!
Et voici ton indemnitי de dיpart. Ah !
Wait. You're not supposed to end with "Ha!"
Attends. Tu ne dois pas terminer par "Ah !"
You're not?
Ah non ?
You're supposed to end with "Argh!"
Tu dois finir par "Grrr" !
Got it! Argh!
Compris ! Grrr !
That's great!
C'est gיnial !
Thanks! I just went with the flow.
Merci ! J'ai suivi mon inspiration.
Ladies and gentlemen, and those in coach...
Chers passagers et la classe ordinaire,
on the left side of the plane...
du cפtי gauche de l'avion,
you can see we're approaching fabulous Las Vegas.
vous voyez dיjא la fabuleuse Las Vegas.
Land ho!
Terre !
Ahoy, matey.
Attention, matelot.
Bye, Dad! Thanks for the lift!
Au revoir, papa ! Merci !
- Okay. What? - Let's move.
- Pas de problטme. Quoi ? - Vite.
- Going to the Heartbreak Hotel? - I'm going to the Heartbreak Hotel.
- ְ l'hפtel Heartbreak ? - C'est lא que je vais.
- Me, too!
- Moi aussi !
Me, too!
Moi aussi !
We've gotta get to the convention center.
On doit se rendre au centre des congrטs.
Should we get a taxi?
On prend le taxi ?
Darn! I spent all my per Diem. That's more our speed.
Zut ! J'ai dיpensי mon allocation. Voilא notre classe.
Right.
Oui.
Excuse me, ladies.
Pardon, mesdames.
Can we get a ride home?
On peut nous raccompagner ?
Jimmy's been sick, and he needs his expensive medicine.
Jimmy est malade et doit prendre son coteux mיdicament.
Where do you live, sweetie?
Oש habites-tu, mon chou ?
The convention center.
Au centre des congrטs.
Bye, sweetie!
Au revoir, mon chou !
Have a fun lady party!
Amusez-vous bien entre dames !
Chicks dig babies.
Les poulettes adorent les bיbיs.
The people of Long Island do not know how to make an iced tea.
On ne sait pas prיparer le thי glacי א Long Island.
Oh, no! How are we gonna find my parents in here?
Non ! Comment trouver mes parents ici ?
Tim!
Tim !
Over there.
Par lא.
Okay, now where's Puppy Co?
Bon. Oש est Chiot et Cie ?
Puppy Co, Puppy Co, Puppy Co...
Chiot et Cie, Chiot et Cie...
Aha! Here it is. Found it!
Ah, ah ! La voici. Je l'ai trouvיe !
But how did you...?
Mais comment as-tu...
Hey! Where'd you go?
Hי ! Oש es-tu passי ?
Not again!
Pas encore !
Come on! I need you!
Allez ! J'ai besoin de toi !
I'm back! I'm back.
Je suis de retour !
What's going on?
Que se passe-t-il ?
That's right.
Oui.
We're gonna launch a brand new puppy in every continent.
Nous allons lancer un chiot tout neuf sur tous les continents.
In every country!
Dans tous les pays !
We're going to take over the world, one heart at a time.
Nous conquerrons le monde, un cur א la fois.
- Tim, there they are! - Mom, Dad!
- Tim, les voilא ! - Maman, papa !
Imagine a puppy that never grows up...
Imaginez un chiot qui ne grandit pas,
never gets old.
qui ne prend pas d'גge.
A puppy that stays a puppy forever.
Un chiot qui reste bיbי א jamais.
I give you the only thing you'll ever love...
Voici ce que vous aimerez plus que tout au monde.
the Forever Puppy!
Le Chiot יternel !
Mommy?
Maman ?
Avert your eyes, Templeton!
Ne regarde pas, Templeton !
Hey! What are you doing here?
Hי ! Que fais-tu ici ?
Mom, Dad!
Maman, papa !
What are they doing here?
Que font-ils ici ?
What are Tim and the baby doing here?
Que font Tim et le bיbי ici ?
What are any of us doing here, really?
Que faisons-nous tous ici, au juste ?
What is going on here?
Que se passe-t-il ici ?
He's got my parents!
Il dיtient mes parents !
We're really here to get them.
On est ici pour les attraper !
Get them!
Attrape-les !
Get the Forever Puppy!
Emparez-vous du Chiot יternel !
We've got to get backstage.
Il faut aller en coulisse.
In there!
Par lא !
Run!
Cours !
Go, go, go!
Allez, allez, allez !
Left, right! Left, right! Left, right!
Gauche, droite ! Gauche, droite !
Yes!
Oui !
Fart. Poop. Doodie.
Pet. Caca. Crotte.
Look at all that formula.
Regarde la quantitי de prיparation lactיe.
Now that's how you launch a product.
Voilא comment on lance un nouveau produit.
Oh, no!
Non !
He's putting them under the rocket!
Il les place sous la fusיe !
Elvis has left the building!
Elvis a quittי les lieux !
Mom, Dad...
Maman, papa...
I'm coming!
J'arrive !
Atta boy! Go, Tim! Go, go!
Bravo ! Allez, Tim ! Vite, vite !
Launch initiated.
Lancement amorcי.
I'm launching my Forever Puppies, and there's nothing you can do about it!
Je lance mes Chiots יternels, et vous ne pouvez pas m'en empךcher !
No!
Non !
Baby Corp stole all the love from me...
Bיbי et Cie m'a volי l'amour,
and now I'm going to take it back from them.
et je vais le rיcupיrer.
You should understand what I'm talking about.
Tu devrais me comprendre.
You got replaced just like me!
On t'a remplacי, comme moi !
No! I'm nothing like you!
Non, ne vous comparez pas א moi !
Bratty kid!
Espטce d'enfant gגtי !
Let our parents go! His parents. The parents.
Libטre nos parents ! Ses parents. Les parents.
Yeah!
Oui !
You could have had your parents' love all to yourself again!
Tu aurais pu accaparer l'amour de tes parents !
But no!
Mais non !
You blew it!
Tu as tout gגchי.
You let that baby boss you around.
Tu laisses ce bיbי te donner des ordres.
He doesn't work for me.
Il ne travaille pas pour moi.
We're partners!
On est associיs !
I'm not ticklish.
Je ne suis pas chatouilleux.
Hey! Where's the baby?
Hי ! Oש est le bיbי ?
Everyone has a tickle spot!
On a tous un point faible !
My ears!
Mes oreilles !
Stop it!
Arrךte חa !
Little brats!
Petits chenapans !
Nothing is going to get in the way of my vengeance.
Rien ne pourra m'empךcher de me venger.
Not you, not anybody!
Ni vous ni personne !
Baby Corp is through.
Bיbי et Cie est fichue.
I win! Ha!
Je suis le vainqueur ! Ah !
Wrong!
Tu te trompes !
You're not supposed to end with "Ha!"
Tu n'es pas censי terminer par "Ah !"
- That's right! - What?
- C'est vrai ! - Quoi ?
You're supposed to end with...
Tu es censי terminer par...
Argh!
Grrr !
En garde!
En garde !
You're fired!
Tu es virי !
And here's your severance package!
Et voici ton indemnitי de dיpart !
Take that, you scurvy scallywag!
Prends חa, espטce de polisson !
Argh!
Grrr !
One minute and counting.
Une minute avant le dיcollage.
- Help! - Anybody!
- ְ l'aide ! - Quelqu'un !
Tim! What are you doing?
Tim ! Que fais-tu ?
No!
Non !
Mom, Dad, I'm coming!
Maman, papa, j'arrive !
Is that you?
C'est toi ?
Don't worry, Mom and Dad. I got this!
Ne vous en faites pas, je suis lא !
- Are you okay? - Is the baby all right?
- ַa va ? - Le bיbי est sain et sauf ?
Yes, the baby's fine.
Oui, sain et sauf.
Who was that?
Qui יtait-ce ?
That was me!
C'יtait moi !
The baby's fine.
Le bיbי va bien.
It won't budge!
ַa ne bouge pas d'un poil !
What's happening?
Que se passe-t-il ?
Wait a second!
Un petit instant !
Hey.
Hי !
I know a way to move my parents.
Je sais comment les dיplacer.
- How? - We can use the puppies!
- Comment ? - Avec les chiots !
Upsies.
En haut.
I need upsies.
Je dois monter.
But what if you "go baby" again?
Mais si tu redeviens bיbי ?
It'll be fine. Fine, fine.
ַa ira. Bon, d'accord.
Fine!
D'accord !
It'll be fine.
Tout ira bien.
Hang on to your diaper!
Accroche ta couche !
We're moving!
ַa bouge !
Why are we moving?
Pourquoi est-ce qu'on bouge ?
All right, Mom and Dad, hang on!
Maman et papa, accrochez-vous !
T-minus 30 seconds.
Dיcollage dans 30 secondes.
Oh, no! Wait!
Non ! Attendez !
Hold on!
Attends-moi !
Go, Tim! Get your parents...
Vas-y, Tim ! Fais sortir
out of here.
tes parents d'ici !
You've gotta jump!
Tu dois sauter !
Come on, it's a piece of cake!
Allez, c'est bיbי facile !
No! No patty cake! Get down!
Non, pas de tape-tape ! Descends !
Don't cry. I'm sorry. Please don't cry!
Ne pleure pas. Excuse-moi. Ne pleure pas !
20 seconds.
Dans 20 secondes.
15 seconds.
Dans 15 secondes.
Blackbird singing in the dead of night
Un merle chante sous les יtoiles
Take these broken wings and learn to fly
Malgrי tes ailes cassיes Tu dois apprendre א voler
All your life
Toute ta vie
You were only waiting For this moment to arise
Tu as attendu la chance De t'יlancer dans le firmament
- Three... - Gotcha!
- Trois... - Dans mes bras !
...two, one.
... deux, un.
Blast off!
Dיcollage !
Yeah!
Oui !
Hey, are you still in there?
Hי ! Es-tu toujours lא ?
Aha!
Ah !
What happened? Did we win?
Que s'est-il passי ? On a rיussi ?
- We won! - We won?
- On a rיussi ! - Rיussi ?
- We won, we won, we won! - We won! Yes!
- On a rיussi ! On a rיussi ! - On a rיussi ! Oui !
Victory nap!
Dodo de la victoire !
You ruined everything!
Tu as tout gגchי !
It's not fair! It's not fair!
Ce n'est pas juste ! Ce n'est pas juste !
That's not right.
C'est moche.
Now you're really going to pay!
Tu vas me le payer cher !
Oh, yeah? It's time you pick on someone your own size!
Ah oui ? Attaque-toi א quelqu'un de ta taille !
What?
Quoi ?
Eugene! You put me down!
Eugene ! Dיpose-moi !
You hear me? I am the boss of you!
M'entends-tu ? Je suis ton patron !
This time, we'll raise him right.
Cette fois-ci, nous l'יlטverons comme il faut.
I'm sure that's gonna turn out fine.
Je suis sr que tout ira bien.
Tim, what's happening?
Tim, que se passe-t-il ?
Mom, Dad, hold on!
Maman, papa, un peu de patience !
Yes!
Oui !
- Tim? - Tim!
- Tim ? - Tim !
Tim! Are you okay?
Tim ! ַa va ?
I'm fine. We're fine.
Je vais bien. Nous allons bien.
You saved us.
Tu nous as sauvיs.
You're our hero.
Tu es notre hיros.
And a great big brother.
Et un grand frטre extraordinaire.
We love you both so much.
On vous aime fort tous les deux.
Both of us?
Tous les deux ?
With all our heart.
De tout notre cur.
Let's go home.
Rentrons א la maison.
How do I look?
De quoi j'ai l'air ?
You look great.
Tu as fiטre allure.
Well, team, good job.
Bon travail, la bande.
Staci, this letter should get you into the school of your choice.
Staci, cette lettre t'ouvrira les portes de l'יcole de ton choix.
- Kindergarten? - That's right.
- La garderie ? - C'est חa.
And if there's anything else...
Si je peux faire autre chose...
How about a raise?
Une augmentation ?
Staci, you don't get paid.
Staci, tu n'es pas payיe.
- One million ziggity-five! - Eight!
- Un million de zillions ! - Huit !
- A tricycle! - Skates!
- Un tricycle ! - Des patins !
- Candy corn? - Lollipop!
- De la tire ? - Un suחon !
Deal.
Marchי conclu.
Best boss ever.
Le meilleur patron du monde.
And you guys don't always have to toe the company line, you know?
Et ne rיpיtez pas le laןus de l'entreprise.
It's okay to think for yourself.
Vous pouvez penser par vous-mךmes.
- No, sir! - No way!
- Non, patron ! - Nenni !
That's a terrible idea!
Quelle idיe יpouvantable !
That's the attitude.
Belle attitude.
- You're so right! - You've got it, sir!
- Vous avez raison ! - Entendu !
- You're the man! - Absolutely!
- Un vrai champion ! - Oui !
Here you go, big guy.
Voilא, mon gros.
You've earned it.
Tu l'as mיritי.
You wanna hug me, don't you?
Tu veux me faire un cגlin, hein ?
I'll miss you too, buddy. Okay.
Tu me manqueras aussi, l'ami.
- There, there. - It'll be okay, big guy.
- Lא, lא. - Tout va bien aller, mon gros.
So...
Alors...
you did it.
Tu as rיussi.
No. We did it.
Non. Nous avons rיussi.
By the way, congratulations on your promotion.
En passant, fיlicitations pour ta promotion.
The corner office, the private potty. All that stuff.
Le bureau du coin, le petit pot א toi. Tout חa.
But, hey! How about you?
Mais... Toi, alors ?
You have your parents all to yourself.
Tu as tes parents א toi tout seul.
So what am I gonna tell Mom and Dad after you leave?
Que vais-je dire א maman et papa aprטs ton dיpart ?
Don't worry.
Ne t'inquiטte pas.
Baby Corp has a procedure for situations like this.
Bיbי et Cie a une procיdure pour de telles situations.
It'll be like I was never born.
Ce sera comme si je n'יtais jamais nי.
I almost forgot!
J'ai failli oublier !
No way! Lam-Lam!
Incroyable ! Laine-Laine !
- You fixed her. - Yep.
- Tu l'as rיparיe. - Oui.
She's as good as new. She's a tough one.
Elle est comme neuve. Une vraie dure א cuire.
Well, I guess we both got what we wanted.
Nous avons tous les deux ce que nous voulions.
It's a win-win.
Tout le monde est content.
Probably should...
Je devrais sans doute...
Yeah.
Oui.
So, stay in school.
Ne lגche pas l'יcole.
I don't really have a choice.
Je n'ai pas vraiment le choix.
Yeah, right.
Oui, c'est vrai.
- Goodbye, Tim. - Bye.
- Au revoir, Tim. - Au revoir.
Yeah, right.
Oui, c'est vrai.
He left as suddenly as he arrived.
Il est parti aussi vite qu'il יtait apparu.
Bye.
Au revoir.
Finally, my life was perfect again.
Ma vie יtait enfin parfaite de nouveau.
Forget about the baby.
Oubliez le bיbי.
Oopsies!
Oups !
Pardon me, big fella.
Pardonne-moi, mon grand.
Surprise!
Surprise !
Hooray!
Hourra !
Forget about the baby?
Oublier le bיbי ?
No, thanks. I'm good.
Non merci. ַa va.
Okie-dokie.
D'accord.
Argh.
Grrr.
Dear Boss Baby...
Cher Bיbי "boss",
I don't usually write very much...
je n'ai pas l'habitude d'יcrire,
but now I know that memos are very important things.
mais je sais que les notes de service sont trטs importantes.
Even though I never went to business school...
Mךme si je n'ai pas fait d'יtudes commerciales,
I did learn to share in kindergarten.
j'ai appris le partage א la garderie.
And if there isn't enough love for the two of us...
Et s'il n'y a pas assez d'amour pour nous deux,
then I wanna give you all of mine.
je veux te donner tout mon amour.
I would like to offer you a job.
J'aimerais t'offrir un emploi.
It will be hard work...
Ce n'est pas de la tarte
and there will be no pay.
et ce n'est pas payי.
But the good news is that you can never be fired.
Mais ce qui est bien, c'est que tu ne seras jamais virי.
And I promise you this.
Et je te fais une promesse.
Every morning when you wake up, I will be there.
Chaque matin, א ton rיveil, je serai lא.
Every night at dinner, I will be there.
Chaque soir, au souper, je serai lא.
Every birthday party, every Christmas morning...
ְ chaque fךte d'anniversaire, le matin de Noכl,
I will be there.
je serai lא.
Year after year after year.
Annיe aprטs annיe.
We will grow old together.
Nous grandirons ensemble.
And you and I will always...
Et toi et moi serons toujours...
...be brothers.
... des frטres.
Always.
Pour toujours.
Wake up, little halflings! It's 7:00 a.m.
Debout, petits enfants-nains ! Il est 7 h.
What's the point, Wizzie?
ְ quoi bon, le mage ?
Because it's 7:00 a.m.
Parce qu'il est 7 h.
I have one job to do, and you make it so difficult.
J'ai une seule tגche א accomplir, et tu me compliques la vie.
It's okay, little halfling.
ַa va, petit enfant-nain.
Sometimes, I get confused too.
Parfois, je suis perplexe, moi aussi.
Especially during daylight savings time.
Surtout durant la saison de l'heure avancיe.
Spring forward, fall back.
Avance au printemps, recule א l'automne.
We don't even have calendars in the wizard's realm!
Point de calendrier dans le royaume du mage !
There is no spring, only darkness and winter!
Le printemps n'existe pas, seuls l'obscuritי et l'hiver existent !
I'm not confused at all, Wizzie.
Je ne suis pas perplexe, le mage.
I just miss him.
Il me manque, c'est tout.
Tim, look who's here!
Tim, regarde qui est lא !
It's your new baby...
C'est ton nouveau petit...
Brother!
Frטre !
You're here! You're really here!
Tu es ici ! C'est vraiment vrai !
Gentle, gentle.
Tout doux, tout doux.
You came back!
Tu es revenu !
Say hello to Theodore Lindsey Templeton.
Dis bonjour א Theodore Lindsey Templeton.
Lindsey?
Lindsey ?
Who's ticklish? Who's ticklish?
Es-tu chatouilleux ?
Here you go.
Voilא.
So, that's my story.
C'est mon histoire, voyez-vous.
Our story.
Notre histoire.
Luckily for me and my little brother, it had a happy ending.
Heureusement pour moi et mon petit frטre, elle a une fin heureuse.
Is that a true story, Daddy?
C'est une histoire vraie, papa ?
Well, sweetie, that's how I remember it.
C'est ainsi que je m'en souviens.
- But you know what I found out? - What?
- Tu sais ce que j'ai dיcouvert ? - Quoi ?
There's plenty of love for everyone.
Il y a amplement d'amour pour tout le monde.
Even me?
Mךme pour moi ?
Especially you.
Surtout pour toi.
Just ask your Uncle Ted.
Demande א ton oncle Ted.
Hey, kid, I hear you're gonna have a baby sister.
Hי ! Il paraמt que tu vas avoir une petite sur.
I wanted a horse.
Je voulais un cheval.
Here you go, kid. Go get yourself a horse.
Tiens, ma chouette. Va t'acheter un cheval.
You know, I'm proud of you, Leslie.
Tu sais, je suis fier de toi, Leslie.
Back at ya, Lindsey.
Moi aussi, Lindsey.
Hi there, baby sister.
Bonjour, petite sur.
Argh!
Grrr !
All right, guys.
Bon, les garחons.
Time for bed.
C'est l'heure du dodo.
Come on, Mom. Just a little longer.
Allez, maman. Encore un peu.
Okay.
D'accord.
Wake up, little halflings! It's time to leave.
Debout, petits enfants-nains ! Il est le temps de partir.
Go and live your peasant lives.
Allez vivre votre vie de paysans.
Be gone with you!
Allez, ouste !
Support us and become VIP member to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Traduction : Christine Archambault, Deluxe Dave Richard